hello everybody, this is Peter here
and today let's start our study of vim
the best editor that ever made
so let's just start at the very beginning, and
have a look at how to open a file with vim
it's like this, so you type vim
you see filename, then you just press enter
and here we are
so let's quit... quit
just capital z, z, twice
OK, let's quit vim, but of course that is not all you need to know
not all the ways how you can open sth with vim
you can also use this this way
like vim,  and "newfilename"
I mean, vim will creat a new file for you
like this, and you can also type sth here
I will show you how to edit a file in vim later
so like any powerful unix tool,
you can start vim with lots of options
and you can check all the options this way
the option I love is sth like this
remote and a few others
but that's not what we are going to talk in this episode
we will talk about (them) later
so I, I think, ahm...
let's... why not stop here, and we'll check how to do things later.
so have a good day, bye!