hello everybody
um...this is Peter here... peter again
so today we are going to explore more powerful stuff about ...
about vim... the best editor that ever, you know ...created
um ... so, let's start vim
ah... we are going to create a new file named hello.c
and  within this file
now what I want to talk about here is when you start vim
you directly come into the "normal mode"
so, you may wonder what the normal mode means
if you don't know normal mode means. Now I can tell you, it's just ...
when you start vim, vim directly take(s) you to normal mode
and now, you can try to type something, like 'd' and 'c'
Ah, you type something but nothing happened
So, you may feel strange here,
but this is actual not bug of vim
but rather it's a nice feature of vim.
it means vim has something called "modes"
so let's check how vim modes works
you just type help, "h" stands for "help"
help vim-modes, OK?
so you can see there are many modes here... many modes
but most ... now in this screencast I want to talk about really
only two of those modes
two most important one(s)
one is normal mode, the other one is I think...
insert mode, like this
so when you first come into ah...
into vim, ah... you first go into normal mode
normal mode also is called command mode
which means everything you type here will be considered as a command
and like 'x' for deleting one word(shall be a character)
and there are also some other commands that can take you into insert mode
like the most often used one is 'i'
press 'i', and vim will go into insert mode
and you can see in the lower left corner of this screen
you see a "insert"
insert, that means vim is now in insert mode
in insert mode, you can generally type something
like "sss", whatever you type here
will be considered as some visible characters, will show up eventually into your file
ah... in your file created, but when you press "esc"
you go back normal mode again
now whatever you type here, as we already mentioned, will be considered as command(s)
like you type 'x'
then ah... you delete one word(shall be one character) rather than insert "x" into your file
so that is the difference, as you type "dd", so "dd", whole line
as you type 'u', it means undo
you can type "ctrl + r", means redo
anyway, don't worry if you can not remember all these things
we will talk about these in details later
anyway in this talk, I just want you know
vim has modes and most important two modes I want you know
here is just two
normal mode and insert mode
so, you still remember how to go into insert mode? you type 'i'
and like this, you press "Esc" and you go back to normal mode
normal mode is also called command mode
which means you type everything as commands
so this is all I want to talk about here
I hope you are not confused, but anyway
it doesn't matter. we will talk about more later
so have a good day. bye