uh... good afternoon everybody
one of the most obvious problems of my earlier screencasts is that
is that... the way I talk. I generally think it feels boring
to make screencasts and just talk to myself
and later I found it was wrong
and actually I should pretend you are just by my side and we talk like friends
later screencasts made this way shall be better anyway
and today ah... of course with no suprise
we continue to talk about vim
we start vim, and now we know vim has many modes
help vim modes. and the most important ones
of course, are normal mode
and insert mode
insert mode, this one yeah!
insert mode, but today I'd like to talk more about why vim has these modes
can we  just go without modes?
and the reason is like this
usually in the most other editors you don't have modes
you just work in one mode that is as it looks
and we call it insert mode, like vim insert mode
you always stay in  insert mode
then sometimes you need some shortcut to make you work more efficiently
like you want delete one word
maybe you press "ctrl+d" or "ctrl+w"
and sometimes you need to do something more powerful
and you need to use like "ctrl +command +s"
and "ctrl +option +command+s" , something like these
you can't avoid these, if you really want some more powerful shortcuts
that's what is happening in some other editors all the time
it can do your work, but the problem is you struggle to use your fingers
and it feels really awful and it is not so efficient
and that's the problem.
that's why vim has its modes. and its normal mode is command mode
like this command mode. in this way you can do things much much simpler
and of course with price of have (having) different modes
that's a good price to pay
it's really rewarding. so no problem
at least I like it so much
and you can use "xx"
and "dd" to delete one word(one line).  you no longer need to struggle to your fingers
uh... painfully, so that's why vim has modes
and of course until now you still only need to know two modes
insert mode and normal mode
so that's why vim has many modes
ok, let's call it a day. talk to you later. bye