ladies and gentlemen, boys and girls. now we are in vim
so today I want to talk about a little bit
why vim takes us first directly into normal mode
uh..., the fact is that in the normal mode you can actually modify your stuff fair easily
and efficiently. if you are in the insert mode, the movement,
uh..., will be, will have to use arrow key or something like this
it won't be so efficient. so in normal mode, everything can be done
much much simpler. uh..., so and in the career of a programmer
most of time will be spend on changing things rather than inserting things
inserting words, that's why normal mode first
so, now we are in normal mode
let's see how to move around in the normal mode
and first let's check the help file "help motion.txt"
uh..., if you want detailed information about how to move around
and also something about operators which we will talk about
maybe later in our next talk. you can check the manual here
but if everything can be found in the manual
what's the point of our screencasts?
our screencast is made so as to you don't need to read all the stuff in the manual
because in the manual there will be lot of details that... ah... peter wants you to learn later
not now. some of the details are really important
but i think it for beginners it is better to leave them alone
so you just need to follow peter and check out the basic stuffs and
build up your knowledge base step by step
later you will get to know all the basic things. you can say
" em... how can i do things a little bit more efficiently "
then you can check the manual and get all the powerful stuff out of it
so, let's talk about motion, let's talk about how to move around in vim
so as you can see, uh... we can move left
this way, move right. this way, move up
sorry, move down, move up, it's just 'h', 'j', 'k' , 'l'
and this is the basic movement and can we just move one word
a time just type 'wwww'
can we just move, uh..., the other way, like move half a page down
use "ctrl +d ", I think. I don't use "ctrl +d " very often
because I just love to move line by line
every time if you use "ctrl + d" and move inside big file, i got confused
I lost my track. en, that's not so good
uh..., how you move inside big files
let's make a big file. you don't need to know what I'm doing here
I am just making a big file
how can we move very quickly inside a big file
I use search. It's maybe called "moving by searching"
you do it this way. if I want move somewhere where I can find another main
uh..., I can do it this way
type "main", then press "enter", and now "nnn"
so, usually if I want to move inside big files
I do this way rather than just type "ctrl + d"
for moving down half page. and "ctrl +u " for moving up half page also
I don't use them very often
so, that's the basic movement
and..., so let's stop here. and talk to you later, bye