hi, you, good afternoon. so, now, I am not feeling very uh... very great
uh... since I have a little bit stomachache
uh... my stomach hurts a bit. it's OK, not so horrible
uh... you know, human beings are just animals
except that we can think, we talk, we work
uh..., so when our life get messy . I think at least for me it is true
I tend to think about doing something that make some sense
so it can probably set our heart peaceful and put us on the right track
so, and doing technology is one of things do make me feel peaceful
because technology is just something fun, it's no big deal, right?
just like this, OK, so if you don't mind
let's start, continue our study of vim
OK, let's see what we can do, let's start vim
check what's in this
uh... it's bullshit, OK
we don't need. OK, so, now let's create a new file
we don't always create '.c' file, we can create any file
OK, and maybe we type something, go to insert mode and type something
I'm sure you now know how to go to insert mode
and maybe you already read the help file and
you know the difference between switching among those modes, normal mode and insert mode
and a bit more, other modes
so, today I want to talk about is still motions
motions, how to move around
let's say, we have "hello world"
and how to, you know how to move to the beginning of this line
it's zero. and end, dollar. zero, dollar
zero, I'm sorry. uh... so, you know how to move one word a time. "ww" and
now, guess how to move two words a time. it's  '2w'
I'm sorry, it's not clear
it's like this. "hello world peter is your friend", move to the beginning , it's three 'w'
'3w' and maybe '2w', like this
and now guess how to move two lines down one time
in one go, it's just,
we go to the... first go to the top of this file
done by "gg", and two 'j'
two 'j', it's "gg"
two 'j' and "gg", three 'j' and it's like this
now, you can see it's just a number with a motion, and that will just do
what you want in a very obvious and maybe a little bit childish way
and it's the motion
uh... but what I want talk about here is the general rule of vim operation
it's one operator and then followed with a motion
let's check the general rule. first you don't know what the operator is maybe
so let's check what operator is, let's check maybe help operators, I'm not sure
help operators, help operator, OK I think we are luck
operators are some things like change, like 'c', change a word
like "d", delete a word, "yank",something like copy
yank means copy, and lots of other more
those are... I think those are operators, but currently we focus on something simple
like change and delete
uh... let's show how to work using operators and motions the same time. OK
like, let's try to delete two words. in one go, it is 'd' two 'w'. OK
uh... undo this thing. 'd' three word
OK, and how can we delete from this line to the end of this file
'd' then the motion 'G' to the end of file
yeah, easy, yeah
it's how to delete from this line to top of this file. 'd' and "gg"
OK, so let's try d (delete) four word
OK, I think you can see the rules, very,  it's very childish, but it is very convenient.
so, let's see how to delete two lines. let's go up, go up
delete two lines, 'd' two 'j', two lines
like three lines, anyway, it's 'd' two 'j', like this
so, if you want know more, if peter here is not giving you very clear explanation
you can check more in documentation yourself. it's like help motions. motions, I think
motions dot txt, you can get things here. how to move around and how to use operators with motions
uh... you know what I mean by talking about motions, motions, we can check motions
characters motions
uh... it doesn't so matter. but uh...
OK, anyway you can get anything here, like what's operator, operator, it's not so easy to get operator
you can get this way. operator... motions and operators.
you can check this part
this part for more information. so that's the general rule of vim
uh... how to use vim in this normal mode. the general rule is one operator then followed with some motion
command, motion commands can be multiplied by numbers
three 'w' like two 'w'. it's like this, like this
like, now I want to change three words. 'c' three 'w'
you see, then we type something new. "hello", then press "Esc"
then you see three words changed into one word, in this way
anyway, still the same thing, change words, like this "hello", OK
easy, uh?
those general rule of vim, of course you can use those many many different ways, because there are
still other more operators and other more motions, check help file and enjoy the power. so
anyway, OK. let's call it today. my stomach still hurts.
uh... but I've done something meaningful and I feel my life is meaningful. OK
OK, stop talking all these nonsense. have a good day.
talk to you later