hi, hi, peter again
in our earlier talk we mentioned operators and motions
and how can we use both of them to constitute, uh... construct a whole vim command
are you still remembering general rules?
uh... let's say "hello world", something like this
you have, first type one operator, then a number, then motion
it's something like this. like "dj", anything like this
uh... we talk about that, but we didn't cover enough of those motions and  operators
of course not all of those operators, and all of them, uh... there are hundred of them
maybe not hundred of them, but certainly lots of them
we don't need to remember all of them, but there are still,
maybe a few of them that are really really useful.
so that I really need to talk about in our screencast
just now, I just think about that how to do this screencast
I certainly believe it will be really boring to just talk about operators and motions
in a plain way, I just type one by one, it will be really boring
like 'w', like 'jj' like 'j', something like this it will be boring
so, but suddenly a good idea come to me, and I need to, I think I would rather to talk, give this screencast a topic
it's something uh... stupid. uh... named big and small
big and small, maybe you don't know what big and small means
here, I want to say, just I will talk about 'O', I talk about 'o'
it's lowercase 'o' and capital 'O'
so we just call it small 'o' and big 'O'
and, small 'y' and big 'Y', small 'p' and big 'P', small 'i' and big 'I'
so, uh... I'm Chinese, in China, we always talk about lowercase as something small
and the uppercase as something big
uh... I am not sure the native speakers talk this way
uh... anyway I  don't care
so, but anyway why they arep so important, let me show you
so, first let's talk about how to go into insert mode from normal mode
it's the most often used one is 'i'
but, you know what is big 'I', it's like this, you type uh...
small 'i' and you are in insert right before the cursor
and if you type big 'I', then you start your insert at the beginning of the line
this is really useful
and another useful one is, you type 'a' and the small 'a'
uh... you can insert right after the cursor position
and if you want to start editing at the end of this line
you just type big 'A'
it's like this the small 'a' and big 'A'
uh... OK, small 'a' and big 'A'. OK, now what small 'o' and big 'O' means?
small 'o' means this, you open, you go from normal mode to insert mode, but you open a new line
and this start editing. what big 'O' means? it's like this. you type big 'O' and
you also go to insert mode but you start a new line above the cursor position
so that's the difference. then uh... one common editing task is that you need to copy and paste
uh... in vim you don't call it copy, you call it yank, "yank", yank
uh... maybe you don't know what "yank" means, you can help, try help 'y', like this
and also if you don't know any of those big and small bullshit
you can just help, help 'p', like this
and of course, you get a big 'P' here
and you can also check, maybe help 'w'
you also have small 'w' and big 'W'
that's different words, big word and small word
and they are different. you can check help file for more information
and anything you know vim help system is really powerful, you generally can find anything in the help system
but we are not going show you all of them in our screencast... time is limited. so
let's continue. maybe I think,  I need talk about yank a paste. OK, how to yank a line
it's like this. 'y', OK, now this line is in one of those special buffer
then  I can type, put. it's not paste, it's like paste, but it's not paste
we call it put, then it's small 'p'. I'm sorry
you find to yank the whole line, you need to type 'yy'
and if you want to put, you type 'p'
and let's try again, you have, you have 'yy' here, now 'p'
you type 'p', then you put something below the current line
and, but if you type big 'P', you put something above the current line
so that's the difference
and yeah that's big and small
cut and paste, big and small, and anything
OK, that's my stupid idea of giving such name big and small
of this screencast to make things maybe a little more funny
uh... maybe it's not funny at all
but, OK that's all i want to talk about. so, enjoy, bye